CHIMMY RAI

Brisbane, QLD 4000

0481287229 - mohunk0@gmail.com - **WWW:** https://github.com/ChimmyRai - **WWW:** www.linkedin.com/in/chimmy-rai-10bb6b6b

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY		

Accomplished Computer Science Teacher with 8 years of academic instruction focused on technology use and application. Expert in developing comprehensive curriculum to address current technology evolution and innovation. Personable communicator proven to deliver engaging lessons to target learning objectives and prepare students for success. Motivated Programmer with exceptional background on Web applications. Quickly masters new software packages and hardware technologies.

SKILLS

- Strong work ethic, self-motivated and flexible approach instilled by doing the various side hustle web development works and pet projects.
- Good communication skills and critical thinker developed through consistently coordinating and facilitating IT related workshops in Education Sector and classroom teaching learning.
- Team player with constantly working in an environment of more than 30 colleagues and peers over a span of seven years.
- Scripting languages: PHP, Python, JavaScript, Solidity, R, SQL
- Frameworks: Laravel, WordPress, Modx, Bootstrap, Tailwind CSS
- Programming Environment: Node JS, TALL (Tailwind, Alpine, Livewire, Laravel)

Work History	
1/2017 to 12/2021	Computer Science Teacher

- Delivered engaging curriculum through diverse methods of classroom instruction, computer lab activities and online learning systems.
- Communicated with students to discuss progress and need for tutoring and extra assistance.
- Invigilated and graded projects, quizzes, and examinations.
- Actively participated in the ICT framework and curriculum development workshops conducted by Royal Education Council of Bhutan.
- Facilitated different batches of python programming workshops to the whole ICT teachers of Bhutan (2019-2020)
- Developed, designed, and maintained school website and developed custom WordPress template for the school.
- Progressively upgraded WordPress site to Laravel powered website.
- Designed and developed school management system with Laravel and its various packages.

01/2014 to 12/2016

Computer Science Teacher Ura Central School-Bumthang, Bhutan

- Actively participated in the ICT framework and curriculum development workshops conducted by Royal Education Council of Bhutan.
- Designed and developed school website.
- Taught HTML and JavaScript to higher secondary students for 3 years.
- Delivered engaging curriculum through diverse methods of classroom instruction, computer lab activities and online learning systems.
- Communicated with students to discuss progress and need for tutoring and extra assistance.
- Planned and implemented curriculum to teach up-to-date technology to students.
- Attended professional development technology courses to increase knowledge and learn new technologies.

07/2012 to 12/2012

Software Developer Intern Athang Pvt Ltd-Thimphu Bhutan

- Wrote clear, clean code snippets for web-based applications.
- Developed web-based project using PHP, HTML and JavaScript programming language.
- Worked with developers to identify and remove software bugs.

•	Contributed to deployments by resolving issues for optimal results.
EDUCATION	

March 2022 - Master of Information Technology, Griffith University, Brisbane (Expected Graduation in Dec 2023)

- Develop Blockchain backed Alcohol Provenance Application as a part of final year Work Integrated Learning project. The project allowed me to develop skills in writing smart contracts and deploying them to the private Ethereum Blockchain. I experienced how front end could interact with the smart contracts deployed on the blockchain with the help of libraries like web3 JS and wallet provider like MetaMask. This was my first Decentralized Application and my first entry into block chain applications.
- Learned and used many of the machine learning packages and tools that are available in Python and R.
- Performed social media analysis using vosonSML packages and visualisation tools (Gephi and Tableau)
- Experienced writing queries in NoSQL database (MongoDB) and handling unstructured data.
- Became well versed in the use of Jupyter Notebook and google Colab.
- Learned to create clear and compelling data visualizations and reports suing different data visualization tools for reporting.

2012-2013 Post Graduate Diploma in Education: ICT in Education

Royal University of Bhutan - Samtse College of Education, Samtse, Bhutan

- Learned to create inclusive classrooms that cater to students with diverse learning needs.
- Tested psychological theories to classroom management and teaching strategies during teaching practice.
- Conducted action research on the topic "Improving teaching/learning of programming concepts using Games based programs".

2009-2012 Bachelor of Computer Science

Sherubtse College, Kanglung, Trashigang, Bhutan

 As last semester project, I worked in a team of 4 to clone a social media site (Facebook) which will provide better user experience in smaller devices (phones). The project was during the years when Bootstrap did not exist, and every design was hard coded without any template using pure CSS and JavaScript. The project provided a very good starting point for me to develop better teamwork and good communication skills in my field of work

REFEREES

Mr. Sherab Tshering

Principal

Punakha Central School

Punakha

Tel. +975-77101973

Email: sherab tshering@education.gov.bt

Mr. Thinley

Curriculum Developer (ICT)

Royal Education Council

Paro

Tel. +975-17650442

Email: thinley@rec.gov.bt